(This drama is a work of fiction created based on historical facts.)
(هذه الدراما عمل خيالي تم إنشاؤه بناءً على حقائق تاريخية).
(Most of the details and depictions of the characters are fictional.)
(معظم تفاصيل وتصورات الشخصيات خيالية).
Jong Jong, let us do this.
جونغ جونغ ، دعونا نفعل هذا.
Yes, my lady.
نعم سيدتي.
(Episode 2)
(الحلقة 2)
Here we go.
ها نحن.
So...
لذا...
even the woman who is supposed to have 99 tails...
حتى المرأة التي من المفترض أن يكون لديها 99 ذيل ...
would not be that special.
لن يكون ذلك خاصًا.
Is he coming? Is he on the way?
هل سيأتي؟  هل هو في الطريق؟
He is coming.
إنه قادم.
Remember what I said?
تذكر ما قلته؟
It would be dangerous.
سيكون خطيرا.
You can do it, Jong Jong. You can.
يمكنك فعل ذلك يا جونغ جونغ.  أنت تستطيع.
I am counting on you, Jong Jong.
أنا أعتمد عليك يا جونغ جونغ.
(My Dearest)
(أعز ما عندي)
Have you heard of the sound...
هل سمعت بالصوت ...
- of the marvel of Peru blooming? - What are you doing?
- من أعجوبة تتفتح بيرو؟  - ماذا تفعل؟
What are you doing then? I was helping you.
ماذا تفعل بعد ذلك؟  كنت أساعدك.
Who? Me?
من؟  أنا؟
When did I ask you to help me?
متى طلبت منك مساعدتي؟
What?
ماذا؟
Was there anyone who was supposed to receive you?
هل كان من المفترض أن يستقبلك أحد؟
Of course, I...
بالطبع أنا ...
You are a lucky man.
انت رجل محظوظ.
What? I am a lucky man?
ماذا؟  أنا رجل محظوظ؟
I am the lucky one? Not you?
أنا محظوظ؟  ليس انت؟
You got to talk to me for a long time on the first day we met.
عليك التحدث معي لفترة طويلة في اليوم الأول الذي التقينا فيه.
You sure are lucky.
أنت متأكد أنك محظوظ.
Anyway, I do not know where you rolled in from,
على أي حال ، لا أعرف من أين دخلت ،
but you can hurry up and get lost.
ولكن يمكنك أن تسرع وتضيع.
You have used up all your luck.
لقد استنفدت كل حظك.
Should you not at least thank me for...
ألا يجب أن تشكرني على الأقل على ...
I am talking here.
انا اتحدث هنا.
You call that fixed?
هل تسمي ذلك ثابت؟
I am hugely disappointed, young master.
أشعر بخيبة أمل كبيرة أيها السيد الشاب.
I said it is not fixed properly yet.
قلت أنه لم يتم إصلاحه بشكل صحيح حتى الآن.
I will get it fixed again.
سوف أصلحه مرة أخرى.
It would not happen again.
لن يحدث مرة أخرى.
Darn it. You should have done a better job.
رتقها.  كان يجب عليك القيام بعمل أفضل.
Do it right, will you?
هل هذا صحيح ، أليس كذلك؟
- Dae Ho. - Gosh.
- داي هو.  - يا إلهي.
She is one loud flower, is she not?
هي زهرة واحدة صاخبة ، أليس كذلك؟
Give it to me.
اعطني اياه.
Flower?
ورد؟
Who is the flower?
من هي الزهرة؟
Who is the marvel of Peru?
من هي أعجوبة بيرو؟
Gosh.
يا الهي.
My lady.
سيدتي.
They must be talking about something boring again.
لا بد أنهم يتحدثون عن شيء ممل مرة أخرى.
Let us get back.
دعونا نعود.
I do not like the socks after all.
أنا لا أحب الجوارب بعد كل شيء.
What?
ماذا؟
There she goes.
ها هي ذاهبة.
- I should go and talk to her. - Wait.
- يجب أن أذهب وأتحدث معها.  - انتظر.
Why does she...
لماذا هي ...
look so down?
انظر الى الاسفل؟
She was grouchy just a moment ago.
كانت متذمرة منذ لحظة.
Right. She looks like...
يمين.  انها تبدو مثل...
she wants to get slapped in the face and cry.
تريد أن تُصفع على وجهها وتبكي.
- What? - Or maybe it is the opposite.
- ماذا؟  - أو ربما العكس.
Maybe she wants to slap someone in the face and make that person cry.
ربما تريد صفع شخص ما على وجهه وجعله يبكي.
What are you saying?
ماذا تقول؟
Do you hear yourself?
هل تسمع نفسك
Look.
ينظر.
It is me.
هذا انا.
Why is he so worked up?
لماذا هو مشغول جدا؟
Look.
ينظر.
About that lady who lives here.
عن تلك السيدة التي تعيش هنا.
There are too many ladies in Neunggun-ri.
يوجد عدد كبير جدًا من السيدات في Neunggun-ri.
There is the lady who acts all conceited thinking that she is pretty.
هناك السيدة التي تتصرف كلها مغرورة معتقدة أنها جميلة.
Right. You mean Lady Gil Chae.
يمين.  تقصد السيدة جيل تشاي.
That is her.
هذا هو لها.
Wait. Her name is...
انتظر.  أسمها...
- Gil Chae? - Yes.
- جيل تشاي؟  - نعم.
Yoo Gil Chae.
يو جيل تشاي.
Lord Yoo Kyo Yeon's daughter.
ابنة اللورد يو كيو يون.
She has broken many hearts.
لقد كسرت قلوب كثيرة.
Oh, I see.
حسنا أرى ذلك.
I suppose you are one of them.
أفترض أنك واحد منهم.
"Oh, I see?"
"حسنا أرى ذلك؟"
Hey, you.
يا هذا.
"I see?" What do you see?
"أرى؟"  ماذا ترى؟
He has fallen head over heels for Lady Gil Chae.
لقد سقط رأسًا على عقب للسيدة جيل تشاي.
Clearly,
بوضوح،
even Young Master Jang Hyun could not help but fall for her charms.
حتى السيد الشاب جانغ هيون لم يستطع إلا أن يقع في حب سحرها.
Why are you laughing?
لماذا تضحك؟
Why do you keep giggling like that?
لماذا تستمر في الضحك هكذا؟
What do you mean I could not help but fall for her?
ماذا تقصد بأنني لم أستطع إلا أن أقع في حبها؟
He took care of what he had to do and returned home.
اعتنى بما كان عليه فعله وعاد إلى المنزل.
"Oh, my."
"أوه ، يا".
"Let me undress you."
"دعني خلع ملابسك".
Goodness. That old man.
صلاح.  هذا الرجل العجوز.
He has to make me cringe every day, does he not?
يجب أن يجعلني أتذلل كل يوم ، أليس كذلك؟
- Mind your own business. - What?
- اهتم بشؤونك الخاصة.  - ماذا؟
- The two of them... - Hey.
- الاثنان منهم ... - مرحبًا.
Stop sewing and go find out what is going on with my application.
توقف عن الخياطة واكتشف ما يحدث مع طلبي.
They do not want you.
إنهم لا يريدونك.
Must you be so stubborn?
هل يجب أن تكون عنيدًا جدًا؟
You handed in a blank exam paper. Have you no shame?
لقد سلمت ورقة امتحان فارغة.  ألا تشعر بالخجل؟
You said you were embarrassed of me for not attending school!
قلت إنك أحرجت مني لعدم ذهابي إلى المدرسة!
Also,
أيضًا،
did you not hear what that fox said? Gil Chae or whatever her name is.
ألم تسمع ما قاله ذلك الثعلب؟  جيل تشاي أو أيا كان اسمها.
She said I rolled in out of nowhere...
قالت إنني دخلت من العدم ...
and told me to hurry up and get lost.
وقال لي أن أسرع وأضل.
Then I shall settle down in this village.
ثم سأستقر في هذه القرية.
You will triple the value of dried persimmons and pay us with rice...
سوف تضاعف قيمة الكاكي المجفف ثلاث مرات وتدفع لنا الأرز ...
in return for accepting him into our school?
مقابل قبوله في مدرستنا؟
Yes.
نعم.
Such insolence!
هذه الوقاحة!
The harvest barn may be empty,
قد تكون حظيرة الحصاد فارغة ،
but did you truly think we would take a bribe and accept him?
لكن هل اعتقدت حقًا أننا سنأخذ رشوة ونقبله؟
Well... I apologize.
حسنًا ... أعتذر.
You have too much rice and do not know what to do with it?
لديك الكثير من الأرز ولا تعرف ماذا تفعل به؟
It is not like you can throw away the rice.
ليس الأمر كما لو أنه يمكنك التخلص من الأرز.
I suppose...
أفترض...
we should just accept it.
يجب علينا فقط قبوله.
You made a wise decision.
لقد اتخذت قرارًا حكيمًا.
I must ask you.
يجب أن أسألك.
Why are you so adamant about joining our school?
لماذا أنت شديد العزم على الانضمام إلى مدرستنا؟
If you wish to pass the state exam,
إذا كنت ترغب في اجتياز امتحان الدولة ،
there are more reputable schools.
هناك المزيد من المدارس ذات السمعة الطيبة.
I have no interest in taking the state exam.
ليس لدي اهتمام بأخذ امتحان الدولة.
However,
لكن،
I have a favor to ask of you.
لدي صالح أن أسألك.
What?
ماذا؟
Another one?
واحدة أخرى؟
What did I say?
ماذا قلت؟
I told you that he must have an ulterior motive.
أخبرتك أنه يجب أن يكون لديه دافع خفي.
You must know Grandpa Song Chu.
يجب أن تعرف الجد سونغ تشو.
This December marks his 60th wedding anniversary.
يصادف شهر ديسمبر هذا العام الذكرى السنوية الستين لزواجه.
I wish to organize a party to celebrate
أرغب في تنظيم حفل للاحتفال بالذكرى الستين لزواجه.
(Hoehonrye: A 60th wedding anniversary party)
(Hoehonrye: حفل الذكرى الستين للزواج)
All his life, he farmed on plots of land owned by the school,
طوال حياته ، كان يزرع على قطع أرض مملوكة للمدرسة ،
so would it be okay if the party took place here?
فهل سيكون الأمر على ما يرام إذا أقيمت الحفلة هنا؟
Oh. Of course,
أوه.  بالطبع،
I understand that only noble families host 60th wedding anniversary parties,
أفهم أن العائلات النبيلة فقط هي التي تستضيف حفلات الذكرى الستين للزواج ،
so Grandpa Song Chu should not be allowed to do it, but...
لذلك لا ينبغي السماح للجد سونغ تشو بالقيام بذلك ، لكن ...
Grandpa Song Chu has been married for 60 years already?
الجد سونغ تشو متزوج منذ 60 عامًا بالفعل؟
I heard his wife was older than him.
سمعت أن زوجته أكبر منه.
Grandma Yi Rang is older than him?
الجدة يي رانغ أكبر منه؟
She looks young.
تبدو شابة.
Did you hear the rumors?
هل سمعت الشائعات؟
Every night, they still...
كل ليلة ، لا يزالون ...
Stop! That is utter nonsense.
قف!  هذا محض هراء.
Is that true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Anyway,
على أي حال،
why would you organize the party for him?
لماذا تنظم الحفلة له؟
Since he works for us,
بما أنه يعمل لدينا ،
we should be the ones organizing it.
يجب أن نكون من ينظمها.
It is true that only noble families can host wedding anniversary parties, but...
صحيح أن العائلات النبيلة فقط يمكنها استضافة حفلات ذكرى الزواج ، لكن ...
They say...
يقولون ...
courtesy comes from affection.
المجاملة تأتي من المودة.
"Courtesy comes from affection?"
"المجاملة تأتي من المودة؟"
Do you not think that this village is filled with the scent of bamboo?
ألا تعتقدون أن هذه القرية مليئة برائحة الخيزران؟
My goodness!
رباه!
Were you...
هل أنت...
waiting for me?
منتظرني؟
What?
ماذا؟
No. I was at the school, taking care of something...
لا ، لقد كنت في المدرسة ، وأعتني بشيء ...
Do not give me that.
لا تعطني هذا.
How did you know that I would pass by here?
كيف عرفت أنني سأمر من هنا؟
Look.
ينظر.
What is the matter with you?
ماذا بك؟
I...
أنا...
was not waiting for you.
لم يكن في انتظارك.
I was simply going my way.
كنت ببساطة أذهب في طريقي.
I was just walking this path,
كنت أسير في هذا الطريق ،
looking ahead...
أتطلع قدما...
Of course, you were.
بالطبع كنت كذلك.
That is what every man says.
هذا ما يقوله كل رجل.
Goodness. You are using an obvious pickup line...
صلاح.  أنت تستخدم خط التقاط واضح ...
that On Dal the Idiot probably used a thousand years ago.
التي ربما استخدمها الأبله في دال منذ ألف عام.
In any case...
على أي حال...
Please excuse me. I have to go.
أرجوك اعذرني.  يجب على  أن أذهب.
"On Dal the Idiot?"
"على دال الأبله؟"
"Pickup line?"
"خط لاقط؟"
Gosh, I am at a loss for words.
يا إلهي ، أنا في حيرة من الكلام.
I have been at a loss for words all day!
لقد كنت في حيرة من الكلمات طوال اليوم!
My lady.
سيدتي.
I am sorry to say this,
أنا آسف لقول هذا ،
but women cannot enter the school premises...
لكن لا يمكن للنساء دخول مباني المدرسة ...
Do not be so square.
لا تكن مربعا جدا.
I can never win with you.
لا استطيع ان افوز معك ابدا
Do not do that.
لا تفعل ذلك.
What you did just now.
ما فعلته الآن.
If you have feelings for me, do not push them aside.
إذا كانت لديك مشاعر تجاهي ، فلا تدفعها جانبًا.
You smiled at me earlier in the day.
لقد ابتسمت لي في وقت سابق من اليوم.
I know very well...
أعرف جيدًا ...
what that smile meant.
ما تعنيه تلك الابتسامة.
Yes.
نعم.
I could not help but smile at the sight of you.
لا يسعني إلا أن أبتسم على مرأى منك.
Who would not smile?
من منا لا يبتسم؟
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
You can have...
بإمكانك أن تأخذ...
any man you want.
اي رجل تريده.
However,
لكن،
I am the only one Lady Eun Ae has.
أنا السيدة الوحيدة التي تمتلكها السيدة إيون آي.
Geun Sam said this to me in the past.
قال هذا لي جيون سام في الماضي.
"You can live without me,"
"يمكنك العيش بدوني"
"but Yak Soon cannot live without me."
"ولكن ياك قريبا لا يمكن أن يعيش بدوني."
Then he dumped me and went to Yak Soon.
ثم هجرني وذهب إلى الياك قريباً.
You know, when men say things like that,
كما تعلم ، عندما يقول الرجال أشياء من هذا القبيل ،
they actually feel...
انهم يشعرون فعلا ...
I had become too complacent.
لقد أصبحت راضيًا جدًا.
I know nothing about Young Master Yeon Jun who lived in Hanyang for years.
لا أعرف شيئًا عن السيد الشاب يون جون الذي عاش في هانيانغ لسنوات.
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
The scholars at Sungkyunkwan will go on...
سيستمر العلماء في Sungkyunkwan ...
to closely assist His Majesty once they pass the exam,
لمساعدة جلالة الملك عن كثب بمجرد اجتياز الامتحان ،
so matchmakers must be eyeing them like hawks.
لذلك يجب أن يتطلع صانعو الثقاب إليهم مثل الصقور.
I need help.
انا بحاجة الى مساعدة.
From someone who is worldly-wise...
من شخص حكيم ...
and well-versed in the sophisticated tastes of the people in Hanyang.
ومتمرس في الأذواق المتطورة للناس في Hanyang.
My gosh!
يا إلهي!
That is absurd!
هذا سخيف!
No way. That cannot happen.
مستحيل.  هذا لا يمكن أن يحدث.
What is the matter?
ما المشكلة؟
Even if he is worldly-wise...
حتى لو كان حكيما ...
and extremely knowledgeable...
ودراية للغاية ...
and knows a lot about Hanyang,
ويعرف الكثير عن هانيانغ ،
I cannot accept help from a fool who does not wish to get married.
لا أستطيع أن أقبل المساعدة من أحمق لا يرغب في الزواج.
Look. I swear, I was not waiting for you,
ينظر.  اقسم اني لم اكن انتظرك
so do not get the wrong idea...
لذلك لا تفهم الفكرة الخاطئة ...
No.
لا.
This is Grandpa Song Chu's house.
هذا منزل الجد سونغ تشو.
Were you waiting for me here?
هل كنت تنتظرني هنا؟
If you wish to spend more time with me,
إذا كنت ترغب في قضاء المزيد من الوقت معي ،
I shall grant you a chance.
سأمنحك فرصة.
Help me, will you?
ساعدني ، هلا فعلت؟
Do I have to? Why would I help you?
هل علي أن؟  لماذا اساعدك؟
Because...
لأن...
I know you are dying to attend the school,
أعلم أنك تتوق للذهاب إلى المدرسة ،
and my father teaches there.
وأبي يعلم هناك.
The thing is, I have already been accepted.
الشيء هو ، لقد تم قبولي بالفعل.
I heard you bribed them.
سمعت أنك رشوتهم.
I already know all about it.
أنا بالفعل أعرف كل شيء عنها.
If you help me this time,
إذا ساعدتني هذه المرة ،
I will help you too.
سوف اساعدك ايضا
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Please come closer.
من فضلك اقترب.
I will tell you the topic of the upcoming exam.
سأخبرك بموضوع الامتحان القادم.
Will you truly...
هل حقا ...
tell me the next exam topic?
قل لي موضوع الامتحان التالي؟
Yes, you have my word.
نعم ، لديك كلامي.
I heard you handed in an empty exam paper.
سمعت أنك سلمت ورقة امتحان فارغة.
That is why people call you a fake aristocrat.
هذا هو السبب في أن الناس يطلقون عليك اسم الأرستقراطي المزيف.
But what help do you want to receive from me in return?
ولكن ما هي المساعدة التي تريد أن تتلقاها مني في المقابل؟
Though I was born and raised in Neunggun-ri,
على الرغم من أنني ولدت وترعرعت في نيونغون ري ،
this village does not suit me.
هذه القرية لا تناسبني.
I should live in a place that is more glamorous and great.
يجب أن أعيش في مكان أكثر روعة وروعة.
Such as...
مثل...
Hanyang?
هانيانغ؟
So I am curious about life in Hanyang.
لذلك لدي فضول بشأن الحياة في هانيانغ.
I want to know what Hanyang people talk about,
أريد أن أعرف ما يتحدث عنه الناس في هانيانغ ،
what kind of clothes they wear, and what they like.
ما نوع الملابس التي يرتدونها وماذا يحبون.
Also, what kind of people they find attractive...
أيضًا ، ما نوع الأشخاص الذين يجدونهم جذابين ...
and want to date.
وتريد المواعدة.
But why do you want to receive help from me...
لكن لماذا تريد أن تتلقى المساعدة مني ...
when you think I'm a womanizer?
عندما تعتقد أنني زير نساء؟
I had poor judgment.
كان لدي حكم ضعيف.
I thought you were approaching me...
ظننت أنك تقترب مني ...
with indecent desires, so I was vigilant.
مع رغبات غير لائقة ، لذلك كنت يقظًا.
But I heard you were...
لكن سمعت أنك كنت ...
a misogamist or whatever.
كره الزواج أو أيا كان.
- Yes. - Then everything is okay.
- نعم.  - ثم كل شيء على ما يرام.
Then there is nothing between us.
ثم لا يوجد شيء بيننا.
There is no way we will ever get married,
لا توجد طريقة نتزوج بها أبدًا ،
so we are not a man and a woman.
لذلك نحن لسنا رجلا وامرأة.
I mean, I am a woman,
أعني ، أنا امرأة ،
but you do not see me as one.
لكنك لا تراني كواحد.
And you are a man,
وانت رجل
but I do not see you as one.
لكني لا أراك كواحد.
We are just...
نحن فقط...
a stone...
حجر...
or weed to each other.
أو الأعشاب لبعضها البعض.
That is why we can help each other without hesitation.
هذا هو السبب في أننا يمكن أن نساعد بعضنا البعض دون تردد.
You will help me, right?
سوف تساعدني ، أليس كذلك؟
- Take care. - Thank you.
- يعتني.  - شكرًا لك.
- Welcome. - Have a look.
- مرحباً.  - الق نظرة.
Have a look.
الق نظرة.
- Please, try one. - We have what you will like.
- من فضلك ، جرب واحدة.  - لدينا ما تريد.
Welcome.
مرحباً.
These days,
هذه الأيام،
it is the trend to wear socks that are smaller than your feet.
هو الاتجاه إلى ارتداء الجوارب التي تكون أصغر من قدميك.
I see.
أرى.
Right. Also,
يمين.  أيضًا،
the daughters of the ministers in Hanyang...
بنات الوزراء في هانيانغ ...
This type of color is...
هذا النوع من الألوان ...
I knew it. I was thinking it would look good on me.
كنت أعرف.  كنت أفكر أنها ستبدو جيدة بالنسبة لي.
They hate this color.
يكرهون هذا اللون.
They use this type of rouge.
يستخدمون هذا النوع من أحمر الشفاه.
Right.
يمين.
These are the storybooks most liked by the Hanyang people.
هذه هي الكتب القصصية التي أحبها شعب هانيانغ.
They contain the ambitions and hopes of the people of Hanyang.
إنها تحتوي على طموحات وآمال أهل هانيانغ.
- Take a look. - Okay.
- إلق نظرة.  - تمام.
"The Story of Woon Yeong?"
"قصة وون يونغ؟"
It is a written account of what a scholar heard...
إنه سرد مكتوب لما سمعه أحد العلماء ...
after meeting a woman named Woon Yeong in his dream.
بعد لقاء امرأة تدعى Woon Yeong في حلمه.
His dream?
حلمه؟
To be honest,
صراحة،
I also dream a vivid dream sometimes.
كما أنني أحلم بحلم حي في بعض الأحيان.
Sometimes, the dream feels real.
في بعض الأحيان ، يبدو الحلم حقيقيًا.
The man...
الرجل...
What are you doing right now?
ماذا تفعل الآن؟
What is wrong with you?
ما بكم؟
Get changed.
تغير.
We will be going to a place where women of a high class are not allowed.
سنذهب إلى مكان لا يُسمح فيه للنساء من الطبقة العليا.
Let me see. Will this...
دعنى ارى.  سيكون هذا...
fit on you? Here.
يناسبك؟  هنا.
Are you telling me to wear a man's clothes?
هل تخبرني أن أرتدي ملابس الرجل؟
Do you not want to live in Hanyang?
ألا تريد أن تعيش في هانيانغ؟
There.
هناك.
No.
لا.
I said lift it up and then wrap it around.
قلت ارفعها ثم لفها.
Like this?
مثله؟
The other way.
الطريق الاخر.
- Like this? - No.
- مثله؟  - لا.
Jeez. Come on.
جيز.  تعال.
How frustrating.
ياله من محبط.
Sit over here.
اجلس هنا.
Are you still not done?
هل مازلت لم تنته؟
I am done.
لقد انتهيت.
If I were born a man, I would have been quite handsome.
إذا ولدت رجلاً ، كنت سأكون وسيمًا جدًا.
That is right.
هذا صحيح.
Ryang Eum, when are you coming out?
ريانغ إيوم ، متى ستخرج؟
- Hurry up. - Look.
- أسرع - بسرعة.  - ينظر.
- Hey, look. - It is Ryang Eum.
- انظر.  - إنه Ryang Eum.
- It is Ryang Eum!
- إنه Ryang Eum!  - إنه Ryang Eum!
- Ryang Eum.
- ريانغ له.  - ريانغ له.
Who is Ryang Eum?
من هو Ryang Eum؟
Consider yourself lucky.
اعتبر نفسك محظوظا.
You will be hearing the voice of the best singer in Joseon.
سوف تسمع صوت أفضل مطرب في جوسون.
You can only hear a voice like his in Hanyang.
يمكنك فقط سماع صوت مثل صوته في Hanyang.
Ryang Eum will be making a special appearance today.
سيظهر Ryang Eum بشكل خاص اليوم.
But...
لكن...
you just attend flower festivals in Neunggun-ri.
أنت فقط تحضر مهرجانات الزهور في نيونجون ري.
I am not sure if you will have a discerning ear.
لست متأكدًا مما إذا كان لديك أذن فارقة.
I am looking from afar
أنا أنظر من بعيد
At your endearing face
في وجهك المحبب
The face that I missed
الوجه الذي فاتني
Was carried
تم حمله
By the distant wind
بواسطة الريح البعيدة
You are like me
انت مثلي
Burying your face in your hands
دفن وجهك بين يديك
The moment
اللحظة
I was waiting for
كنت انتظر
Walk on that path
امش على هذا الطريق
Even when you waver
حتى عندما ترتد
In the moonlight
في ضوء القمر
Are you crying?
هل تبكي؟
I keep
أنا أحتفظ
Thinking of you
أفكر فيك
But you turn away
لكنك تبتعد
My lingering feelings
مشاعري العالقة
Will be dropped
سيتم إسقاطها
One drop at a time
قطرة واحدة في كل مرة
With the passing of time
مع مرور الوقت
This heart that loves you
هذا القلب الذي يحبك
I will only keep it
سأحتفظ به فقط
In my heart
في قلبي
How beautiful.
كم هو جميل.
He is indeed the best singer.
إنه بالفعل أفضل مطرب.
I love it.
أنا أحبه.
I truly love it.
أنا حقا أحبه.
I have never heard of something this beautiful in my life.
لم أسمع قط بشيء بهذا الجمال في حياتي.
He is indeed the best singer.
إنه بالفعل أفضل مطرب.
Let us get going.
فلنبدأ.
Ryang Eum!
ريانغ هو!
What is that dream about?
ما هو هذا الحلم؟
What?
ماذا؟
You said you sometimes have the most vivid dream.
قلت إنك في بعض الأحيان يكون لديك الحلم الأكثر وضوحًا.
Well, that is...
حسنًا ، هذا هو ...
It is nothing.
إنه لا شيء.
What?
ماذا؟
I guess the rumor is true.
أعتقد أن الإشاعة صحيحة.
You are here alone with me.
انت هنا وحدك معي.
And yet you are neither flushing nor stammering.
ومع ذلك فأنت لا تتأرجح ولا تتلعثم.
The rumor goes that you do not believe in marriage...
تقول الاشاعة انك لا تؤمن بالزواج ...
because you are unable to function as a man.
لأنك غير قادر على العمل كرجل.
What?
ماذا؟
Is it wrong?
هل هو خطأ؟
There is no way.
لا توجد طريقة.
What is so funny?
ما هو المضحك كثيرا؟
It is nothing.
إنه لا شيء.
Let us go back now.
دعونا نعود الآن.
My lady.
سيدتي.
The men you have dated so far...
الرجال الذين واعدتهم حتى الآن ...
must be the timid and naive scholars...
يجب أن يكونوا العلماء الخجولين والساذجين ...
who spent their whole lives studying at school.
الذين أمضوا حياتهم بأكملها في الدراسة في المدرسة.
So one glance from you...
لذا نظرة واحدة منك ...
must have made them over the moon.
يجب أن يكون قد جعلهم فوق القمر.
But my lady,
لكن سيدتي ،
I am not them.
أنا لست هم.
Well.
حسنًا.
You will find out soon enough.
سوف تكتشف قريبا بما فيه الكفاية.
What is wrong?
ما الخطأ؟
Do I suddenly look like a man,
هل أبدو فجأة كرجل ،
not just some weed or rock?
ليس فقط بعض الحشائش أو الصخور؟
Here. Take this.
هنا.  خد هذا.
Your clothes.
ملابسك.
When should I return them to you?
متى يجب أن أعيدها لك؟
Tomorrow, I leave on a journey to trade persimmons for rice.
غدًا ، سأغادر في رحلة لتبادل البرسيمون بالأرز.
It will take a few months.
سيستغرق بضعة أشهر.
Then I will see you off tomorrow.
ثم سأوديك غدا.
I have to return the clothes anyway.
لا بد لي من إعادة الملابس على أي حال.
That sounds good.
فكرة جميلة.
What am I thinking?
ما أنا أفكر؟
(Moonlight on pear blossoms, my beloved in my heart)
(ضوء القمر على أزهار الكمثرى حبيبي في قلبي)
"My beloved in my heart?"
"حبيبي في قلبي؟"
What is that, My lady?
ما هذا يا سيدتي؟
A lady must have given it to him.
لابد أن السيدة أعطته إياه.
Why would he carelessly place an item like this?
لماذا يضع شيئًا مثل هذا بلا مبالاة؟
What am I expecting from a man like that?
ماذا أتوقع من رجل كهذا؟
My Lady.
سيدتي.
Yeon Jun is in the reception room.
يون جون في غرفة الاستقبال.
My lady cannot come.
سيدتي لا تستطيع أن تأتي.
The young masters have come.
لقد جاء السادة الشباب.
Let us go.
دعنا نذهب.
I will submit the appeal as it is.
سأقدم الاستئناف كما هو.
I will read it.
أنا سوف قراءتها.
Look how dashing Yeon Jun is.
انظروا كيف محطما يون جون.
What am I thinking when I have him?
ماذا أفكر عندما يكون لدي؟
At a time when the foreign intruder is proclaiming himself as the emperor,
في الوقت الذي يعلن فيه الدخيل الأجنبي نفسه إمبراطورًا ،
if we, the nation of propriety, do not take action,
إذا نحن ، أمة الصالح ، لا نتصرف ،
we will be no different from those beasts,
لن نكون مختلفين عن تلك الوحوش ،
and we will end up losing the trust of our people.
وسننتهي بفقدان ثقة شعبنا.
So we implore His Majesty...
لذلك نناشد جلالة الملك ...
to prepare a plan to fight.
لإعداد خطة للقتال.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty, in all eight provinces, there have been numerous petitions...
جلالة الملك ، في جميع المقاطعات الثماني ، كانت هناك العديد من الالتماسات ...
requesting to confront and fight against the foreign invaders.
المطالبة بمواجهة ومحاربة الغزاة الأجانب.
What is the purpose of sending an envoy to investigate their intentions?
ما هو الغرض من إرسال مبعوث للتحقيق في نواياهم؟
If we do not send envoys now,
إذا لم نرسل مبعوثين الآن ،
they will use it as an excuse to bring their troops and attack.
سوف يستخدمونها كذريعة لجلب قواتهم والهجوم.
All right, then.
حسنا إذا.
We should send a letter, reprimanding them...
يجب أن نرسل خطابًا نوبخهم فيه ...
for failing to fulfill the promise they made in the Year of Jeongmyo.
لفشلهم في الوفاء بالوعد الذي قطعوه في عام Jeongmyo.
Once we lose the trust of the people, it is hard to gain it back.
بمجرد أن نفقد ثقة الناس ، من الصعب استعادتها.
Do you not know that that is a far graver problem than the foreign intruders?
ألا تعلم أن هذه مشكلة أخطر بكثير من الدخلاء الأجانب؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Sending a letter to Great Jin to urge them to keep...
إرسال رسالة إلى جين العظيم لحثهم على الاستمرار ...
the promise of the Year of Jeongmyo...
وعد عام Jeongmyo ...
will ruin everything.
سوف تدمر كل شيء.
I am aware. Of course, I know that.
انا على درايه.  بالطبع أنا أعلم ذلك.
However,
لكن،
I started the coup to punish Gwanghae...
بدأت الانقلاب لمعاقبة جوانجاي ...
for being friendly with those outlanders.
لكونك ودودًا مع هؤلاء الأجانب.
So if I try to curry favor with Great Jin now,
لذا ، إذا حاولت كسب ود جريت جين الآن ،
how will the young officers and scholars react?
كيف سيكون رد فعل الضباط والعلماء الشباب؟
You do not have to listen to everything that the young officers are saying.
ليس عليك أن تستمع إلى كل ما يقوله الضباط الشباب.
Perhaps,
ربما،
a war with them is unavoidable.
الحرب معهم أمر لا مفر منه.
I still vividly remember the pain of having to flee to Ganghwa Island...
ما زلت أتذكر بوضوح ألم الاضطرار إلى الفرار إلى جزيرة كانغهوا ...
ten years ago.
قبل عشر سنوات.
(Pacheon: When a king evacuates the palace and flees during a war)
(باتشون: عندما يخلي الملك القصر ويهرب أثناء الحرب)
They want to conquer Anju no matter what.
إنهم يريدون قهر أنجو مهما حدث.
(Anju: A military strongpoint in Pyongan Province)
(أنجو: نقطة قوة عسكرية في مقاطعة بيونغان)
Collect the supplies in the storage and distribute them...
اجمع المؤن في المخازن ووزعها ...
among the soldiers.
بين الجنود.
Then send the rest to the fortress north of the Chongchon River...
ثم أرسل الباقي إلى الحصن شمال نهر Chongchon ...
so that we can be prepared for their attack.
حتى نتمكن من الاستعداد لهجومهم.
We have been preparing for another invasion since the Year of Jeongmyo,
نحن نستعد لغزو آخر منذ عام Jeongmyo ،
so we must count on them.
لذلك يجب أن نعتمد عليهم.
Even if all fails,
حتى لو فشل كل شيء ،
we still have Ganghwa Island.
لا يزال لدينا جزيرة كانغهوا.
(Simyang Palace, Qing)
(قصر سيميانغ ، تشينغ)
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The King of Joseon is hiring military officials to prepare for war.
ملك جوسون يستعين بمسؤولين عسكريين للاستعداد للحرب.
He ordered to tighten security at each fortress...
وأمر بتشديد الأمن عند كل حصن ...
and to send cannons and food to Ganghwa Island.
وإرسال المدافع والمواد الغذائية إلى جزيرة كانغهوا.
They always have nothing to count on but Ganghwa Island.
ليس لديهم دائمًا ما يعتمدون عليه سوى جزيرة كانغهوا.
However, Your Majesty.
ومع ذلك ، جلالة الملك.
Joseon may be a small country, but when it was Goguryeo,
قد تكون جوسون دولة صغيرة ، ولكن عندما كانت جوجوريو ،
its army managed to fight off Sui's one million soldiers...
تمكن جيشها من محاربة جنود سوي البالغ عددهم مليون جندي ...
and eventually won the seven-year war with Japan.
وفي النهاية ربحوا حرب السنوات السبع مع اليابان.
And that is why we could not go in deep in the Year of Jeongmyo.
ولهذا السبب لم نتمكن من التعمق في عام Jeongmyo.
I am aware.
انا على درايه.
Joseon may be small but should not be underestimated.
قد تكون جوسون صغيرة ولكن لا ينبغي الاستهانة بها.
Hence, we must find a different way this time.
ومن ثم ، يجب أن نجد طريقة مختلفة هذه المرة.
I...
أنا...
can wait.
يمكن أن تنتظر.
I waited until my father finally looked at me and not my seven brothers.
انتظرت حتى نظر والدي أخيرًا إليّ وليس أخوتي السبعة.
Then after I took the throne,
ثم بعد أن توليت العرش ،
I waited for my brothers to accept and acknowledge me as their king.
انتظرتُ إخوتي ليقبلوني ويعترفوا بي كملك لهم.
Now,
الآن،
I can and shall wait until Joseon's rivers freeze.
يمكنني وسأنتظر حتى تتجمد أنهار جوسون.
My patience...
صبري...
has never once betrayed me.
لم يخونني مرة واحدة.
Do you know how to revive someone who is starving to death?
هل تعرف كيف تحيي شخصا يتضور جوعا حتى الموت؟
Feeding them grains first will shock the stomach.
إن إطعامهم الحبوب أولاً سيصيب المعدة.
Then they will vomit and actually die.
ثم يتقيأون ويموتون بالفعل.
Hence, you must give them a bowl of poop water first.
ومن ثم ، يجب أن تمنحهم وعاءًا من ماء الأنبوب أولاً.
Aged poop water.
الذين تتراوح أعمارهم بين أنبوب الماء.
(Uiju)
(أويجو)
When they no longer look so pale,
عندما لا تبدو شاحبة ،
that is when you give them rice porridge. That is how you revive them.
هذا عندما تعطيهم عصيدة الأرز.  هذه هي الطريقة التي تحييهم بها.
That scumbag!
هذا الحثالة!
He came back to life thanks to my poop.
لقد عاد إلى الحياة بفضل أنبوبى.
So how dare he...
فكيف يجرؤ ...
report me to steal my business?
أبلغني لسرقة عملي؟
So? Are you asking me to spank Kkeut Soe's butt or something?
لذا؟  هل تطلب مني أن أضرب بعقب Kkeut Soe أو شيء من هذا القبيل؟
That will not do.
هذا لن ينفع.
I will kill him.
سأقتله.
- No. - No?
- لا لا؟
Why not? Why can I not do it?
ولم لا؟  لماذا لا يمكنني فعل ذلك؟
Have I been paying bribes to get treated like this?
هل كنت أدفع رشاوى لكي أعامل بهذه الطريقة؟
Kkeut Soe pays bribes too. He pays more than you do.
Kkeut Soe تدفع الرشاوى أيضًا.  يدفع أكثر مما تدفعه.
Do you have proof that Kkeut Soe was the one who reported you?
هل لديك دليل على أن Kkeut Soe هو من أبلغ عنك؟
Tsueda said...
قال تسويدا ...
You fool.
يالك من أحمق.
You believe Tsueda?
هل تصدق Tsueda؟
Do you look down on me?
هل تنظر إلي باستخفاف؟
Do you think I am still a mere wandering Jurchen?
هل تعتقد أنني ما زلت مجرد جورشن متجول؟
Ningguchin.
نينغوتشين.
Do not forget.
لا تنسى.
You are...
أنت...
only allowed to play in a small puddle of poop that I give you.
يُسمح فقط باللعب في بركة صغيرة من الفضلات التي أعطيك إياها.
You scumbag!
أيها الأوغاد!
Please leave.
ارجوك ان ترحل.
So? Whose side will he take, between Ningguchin and Kkeut Soe?
لذا؟  إلى جانب من سيأخذ ، بين نينغوتشين وكيكوت سوي؟
I do not know.
لا أعلم.
I will take 100 geun of this.
سآخذ 100 جيون من هذا.
I will pay you with ten boxes of top-quality persimmons from Neunggun-ri.
سأدفع لك بعشرة صناديق من الكاكي عالي الجودة من Neunggun-ri.
Ten boxes of persimmons for a hundred geun of tobacco?
عشرة علب من الكاكي مقابل مائة جيون من التبغ؟
My goodness. That cannot be done. Not even you.
رباه.  لا يمكن القيام بذلك.  ولا حتى أنت.
Instead,
بدلاً من،
I will sell the piles of old tobacco in that room for you.
سأبيع لك أكوام التبغ القديمة في تلك الغرفة.
I heard when you crossed the river to sell tobacco,
سمعت عندما عبرت النهر لبيع التبغ
they took everything and did not even pay you.
أخذوا كل شيء ولم يدفعوا لك حتى.
Will you truly sell them for me?
هل ستبيعهم حقًا من أجلي؟
What do you plan to do with all the tobacco?
ماذا تنوي أن تفعل بكل أنواع التبغ؟
I will exchange them with the rice I sent to Neunggun-ri.
سأبادلهم بالأرز الذي أرسلته إلى نيونغون ري.
We have a problem! It is an emergency.
لدينا مشكلة!  إنها حالة طارئة.
Jang Hyun.
جانغ هيون.
Tsueda has been stabbed.
تم طعن تسويدا.
- My goodness. - Gosh, what do we do?
- رباه.  - يا إلهي ، ماذا نفعل؟
- Oh, dear. - What happened?
- يا عزيزي.  - ماذا حدث؟
- Goodness. - Who did this?
- صلاح.  - من فعل هذا؟
- Oh, boy. - Is he dead or not?
- يا ولد.  - هل مات أم لا؟
He is dead.
انه ميت.
- My goodness. - I have no idea what happened.
- رباه.  - ليس لدي أي فكرة عما حدث.
What on earth happened?
ماذا حدث بحق الأرض؟
- No idea. - My goodness.
- لا يوجد فكرة.  - رباه.
Gosh, who are they?
يا الهي من هم؟
Move!
يتحرك!
Boss wants to get to the bottom of this,
يريد الرئيس الوصول إلى حقيقة الأمر ،
so watch what you say today.
لذا شاهد ما تقوله اليوم.
- Move! - Make way!
- يتحرك!  - أصنع طريقا!
It is nice to see Joseon fools,
من الجميل أن نرى حمقى جوسون ،
Jurchen fools,
الحمقى Jurchen ،
and even fools from Tsushima Island in one place after a long time.
وحتى الحمقى من جزيرة تسوشيما في مكان واحد بعد وقت طويل.
So Tsueda is dead.
لذا مات تسويدا.
For people like us, even if we die a sudden death,
لأناس مثلنا ، حتى لو متنا موتًا مفاجئًا ،
we should be grateful if it was painless.
يجب أن نكون شاكرين إذا كان الأمر غير مؤلم.
But in Uiju,
لكن في أويجو ،
there should not be a single stabbing incident I do not know about.
لا ينبغي أن تكون هناك حادثة طعن واحدة لا أعرف بشأنها.
A few days ago, Tsueda sent me a letter,
قبل أيام قليلة ، بعثت تسويدا برسالة ،
saying he urgently needed to speak to me.
قائلا إنه بحاجة ماسة للتحدث معي.
But...
لكن...
he died on his way to meet me.
مات وهو في طريقه للقائي.
Someone...
شخص ما...
killed him to silence him.
قتله لإسكاته.
I bet it was done by those who are after my business.
أراهن أنه تم من قبل أولئك الذين يسعون وراء عملي.
You think someone is after your business? How petty.
هل تعتقد أن هناك من يسعى وراء عملك؟  كيف تافه.
You siphon off rice collected as tax. You call that a business?
أنت تسحب الأرز المحصل كضريبة.  هل تسمي هذا عمل؟
(Segokmi: Rice collected as tax)
(سيغوكمي: الأرز يتم تحصيله كضريبة)
To siphon off the rice,
لشفط الأرز ،
you have to bribe so many government officials...
عليك رشوة الكثير من المسؤولين الحكوميين ...
from bottom to top.
من الأعلى للأسفل.
We work very hard to bribe them...
نعمل بجد لرشوتهم ...
and keep them on our side. All you do is use them.
وإبقائهم في صالحنا.  كل ما تفعله هو استخدامها.
But you want us out because it is your business?
لكنك تريدنا أن نخرج لأنه من شأنك؟
I knew it!
كنت أعرف!
That is why you reported me!
لهذا السبب أبلغتني!
And you killed Tsueda to silence him!
وقمت بقتل تسيدا لإسكاته!
Do you have evidence?
هل لديك دليل؟
If one of you...
إذا كان أحدكم ...
killed Tsueda,
قتل تسيدا ،
I will finish you off with my own hands.
سأقضي عليك بيدي.
We should take care of it before Kkeut Soe beats us to it.
يجب أن نعتني بها قبل أن تهزمنا Kkeut Soe عليها.
Darn it.
رتقها.
You scumbag.
أيها الأوغاد.
Darn you.
تبا لك.
Do you think you can get away with this?
هل تعتقد أنه يمكنك التخلص من هذا؟
You little rat!
أيها الجرذ الصغير!
You know many Joseon swear words.
أنت تعرف الكثير من أقسم جوسون.
Let me ask you something.
اسمح لي أن أسألك سؤالا.
Do you think the foreign intruders will invade Joseon?
هل تعتقد أن الدخلاء الأجانب سيغزون جوسون؟
What?
ماذا؟
Why are you asking me this?
لماذا تسألني هذا؟
- Why would you ask me... - What do you think?
- لماذا تسألني ... - ما رأيك؟
I am asking you because you are one of them.
أنا أسألك لأنك واحد منهم.
You see, those intruders from Qing...
كما ترى ، هؤلاء الدخلاء من تشينغ ...
used to consider Joseon as their elder brother.
اعتادوا اعتبار جوسون شقيقهم الأكبر.
But now that they think they have become powerful,
ولكن الآن بعد أن ظنوا أنهم أصبحوا أقوياء ،
they are vying for a chance to invade their elder brother.
إنهم يتنافسون على فرصة لغزو أخيهم الأكبر.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
It is just like what you are doing.
إنه تمامًا مثل ما تفعله.
What?
ماذا؟
You said you would attack Kkeut Soe,
قلت إنك ستهاجم Kkeut Soe ،
but in reality, you joined hands with him...
لكن في الواقع ، لقد تعاونت معه ...
and tried to kill Yang Chun. Did you think I would not know that?
وحاول قتل يانغ تشون.  هل تعتقد أنني لن أعرف ذلك؟
But...
لكن...
after Tsueda,
بعد تسويدا ،
your middleman, died,
وسيطك مات ،
your friendship went down the drain.
ذهبت صداقتك إلى البالوعة.
- That is what I am saying. - No.
- هذا ما أقوله.  - لا.
I...
أنا...
said no.
قال لا.
It was Kkeut Soe's...
كان من Kkeut Soe ...
idea. Yes.
فكرة.  نعم.
Do not trust him.
لا تثق به.
I said no.
قلت لا.
It was all his doing!
كان كل ما يفعله!
You punk!
انت فاسق!
Shut your mouth!
اصمت!
Shut it, you punk!
أغلقه ، أيها الشرير!
You look like a webfoot octopus!
أنت تبدو مثل أخطبوط القدم!
I hated you from the start.
لقد كرهتك منذ البداية
You little scum!
أنت حثالة صغيرة!
You do not deserve to live, you...
أنت لا تستحق أن تعيش أنت ...
Right.
يمين.
Your henchmen will be here.
سوف يكون أتباعك هنا.
What?
ماذا؟
Spare me, please.
اعفيني من فضلك.
Please.
لو سمحت.
Do not worry. I called your henchmen too.
لا تقلق.  لقد اتصلت بأتباعك أيضًا.
They said they would kill Ningguchin.
قالوا إنهم سيقتلون Ningguchin.
Since you two are enemies now,
بما أنكما أعداء الآن ،
fight with all your might.
قتال بكل قوتك.
Hey, Gu Jam, they are coming.
مرحبًا ، Gu Jam ، إنهم قادمون.
Where are you?
أين أنت؟
(Usimjeong)
(أوسيمجونغ)
Did you not get hurt? You went through a lot.
ألم تتأذى؟  لقد مررت بالكثير.
No, he did not.
لا لم يفعل.
He just moved his mouth. He did not do anything...
لقد حرك فمه للتو.  لم يفعل شيئا ...
Where is Yang Chun?
أين يانغ تشون؟
You are here.
أنت هنا.
Please spare me, Yang Chun.
أرجوك أنقذني ، يانغ تشون.
Please spare me!
الرجاء إعفائي!
Do you know...
هل تعرف...
how to dance?
كيف ترقص
Sorry?
آسف؟
"Dance?"
"الرقص؟"
Do you want to be my son?
هل تريد ان تكون ابني؟
What do you think...
ماذا تعتقد...
of being a father and son to each other...
من كونهما أبًا وابنًا لبعضهما البعض ...
and living here together...
والعيش هنا معا ...
like a family until we die?
كعائلة حتى نموت؟
You must be getting senile.
يجب أن تكون قد أصبت بالشيخوخة.
Do you not want to?
ألا تريد؟
I do not.
انا لست.
Why not?
ولم لا؟
Fine.
بخير.
I will make sure you never leave Uiju!
سأحرص على ألا تغادر أويجو أبدًا!
Look at how ill-tempered he is. Gosh.
انظر إلى مدى سوء طباعه.  يا الهي.
Hey.
يا.
Do not stop.
لا تتوقف.
Keep dancing.
كن حذرا.
Have you awoken?
هل استيقظت؟
Then...
ثم...
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
My name is Young Rang because I am bright and starry...
اسمي يونغ رانج لأنني مشرق ومليء بالنجوم ...
like the early morning dew.
مثل ندى الصباح الباكر.
Stay still. I know my stuff.
اثبت مكانك.  أنا أعرف أشيائي.
Stop.
قف.
Do you want me to strip you?
هل تريد مني تجريدك؟
Do not. Stop.
لا.  قف.
Go away.
يبتعد.
Get away from me.
ابتعد عني.
Hey...
يا...
Right.
يمين.
What did you say...
ماذا قلت...
your name was again?
كان اسمك من جديد
Young Rang.
يونغ رانج.
Okay. I get that your name is Young Rang.
تمام.  فهمت أن اسمك هو يونغ رانج.
But why were you trying to take your clothes off here?
لكن لماذا كنت تحاول خلع ملابسك هنا؟
What do you mean? I am here to serve you.
ماذا تقصد؟  أنا هنا لخدمتك.
"Serve?"
"يخدم؟"
Do you know...
هل تعرف...
how much everyone fought because they wanted to serve you?
كم قاتل الجميع لأنهم أرادوا خدمتك؟
Stop. Do not move.
قف.  لا تتحرك.
You should...
يجب...
come back after...
أعود بعد ...
Wait. How old are you?
انتظر.  كم عمرك؟
I am 15 years old.
عمري 15 عاما.
Actually, I turned 16,
في الواقع ، لقد بلغت السادسة عشرة من عمري ،
but I still look like I am 15.
لكن ما زلت أبدو وكأنني أبلغ من العمر 15 عامًا.
Why I ought to...
لماذا يجب علي ...
- Master. - Master. Over here.
- يتقن.  - يتقن.  هنا.
I have to get you.
لا بد لي من الحصول عليك.
- We are over here. - Over here.
- نحن هنا.  - هنا.
- Come over here. - Master!
- تعال الى هنا.  - يتقن!
- We are here. - Hey.
- نحن هنا.  - يا.
Here you are.
تفضل.
Yes, here I am, you old man.
نعم ، أنا هنا ، أيها الرجل العجوز.
What? You are here.
ماذا؟  أنت هنا.
Get out.
اخرج.
My gosh.
يا إلهي.
How could you send a little girl to my room?
كيف يمكنك إرسال فتاة صغيرة إلى غرفتي؟
What? Do you not like her?
ماذا؟  ألا تحبها؟
Then I will send another girl.
ثم سأرسل فتاة أخرى.
Gosh, you old man.
يا إلهي ، أنت رجل عجوز.
Do you think I will stay here if you do that?
هل تعتقد أنني سأبقى هنا إذا فعلت ذلك؟
What?
ماذا؟
You are going to leave again?
هل ستغادر مرة أخرى؟
Last time, you said you would be away for a month,
آخر مرة قلت إنك ستغادر لمدة شهر ،
but you were gone for over a year!
لكنك ذهبت لأكثر من عام!
I am old now.
أنا عجوز الآن.
I am old.
أنا عجوز.
Where did the mighty Gu Yang Chun go?
أين ذهب قو يانغ تشون العظيم؟
Tell me.
أخبرني.
This time,
هذا الوقت،
I really will not be gone for a while.
أنا حقا لن أرحل لفترة من الوقت.
Gosh. Why is he bringing him along?
يا الهي.  لماذا يأتي به؟
Jang Hyun!
جانغ هيون!
Yes.
نعم.
Is the bright Young Rang here to say goodbye?
هل الشاب الصغير هنا ليقول وداعا؟
Do you know how well everyone is treating me...
هل تعرف كيف يعاملني الجميع بشكل جيد ...
for spending the night with you?
لقضاء الليلة معك؟
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Then why is there a rumor going around that I am a eunuch?
إذن لماذا هناك شائعة بأنني خصي؟
Ae Ok, that brat.
عزت طيب ، هذا شقي.
I told her not to tell anyone.
قلت لها ألا تخبر أحدا.
- Young Rang. - Yes?
- يونغ رانج.  - نعم؟
Let me make this clear.
اسمحوا لي أن أوضح هذا.
I am not...
انا لست...
Not...
لا...
I did not leave you there...
لم اتركك هناك ...
because I am whatever you think I am.
لأنني كل ما تعتقده أنا.
Do you feel sorry?
هل تشعر بالأسف
If you feel sorry,
إذا شعرت بالأسف ،
can you do me a favor?
هل يمكنك أن تسدي لي خدمة؟
I will do anything.
سوف افعل اي شيء.
Until you lose your lanugo,
حتى تفقد الوبر الخاص بك ،
you better not...
من الأفضل ألا ...
become an official kisaeng.
أصبح kisaeng الرسمي.
Why not?
ولم لا؟
- You are too young... - By any chance,
- أنت صغير جدًا ... - بأي فرصة ،
is it because you want me for yourself?
هل هذا لانك تريدني لنفسك
Then...
ثم...
will you fix your thing down there?
هل ستصلح الشيء الخاص بك هناك؟
I told you that is not true.
أخبرتك أن هذا ليس صحيحًا.
You are mistaken.
انت مخطئ.
- You got it wrong. - Let us go.
- لقد فهمت خطأ.  - دعنا نذهب.
She already found out. There is no need for excuses.
لقد اكتشفت بالفعل.  ليست هناك حاجة لأعذار.
- But... - How lame.
- لكن ... - يا له من أعرج.
It is not true.
هذا غير صحيح.
- How am I supposed to know? - Right?
- كيف يفترض بي ان اعلم؟  - يمين؟
You know it is not true, do you not?
أنت تعلم أن هذا ليس صحيحًا ، أليس كذلك؟
Let go! She thinks it is real!
اتركه!  هي تعتقد أنه حقيقي!
Just let her think that.
فقط دعها تعتقد ذلك.
Jang Hyun, I will be waiting for you!
جانغ هيون ، سأنتظرك!
I will wait for you no matter how long it takes!
سأنتظرك مهما طال الوقت!
So you have to fix your disease!
لذلك عليك أن تصلح مرضك!
I hope your thing down there works fine next time!
آمل أن يعمل الشيء الخاص بك بشكل جيد في المرة القادمة!
Okay?
تمام؟
It is not true!
هذا غير صحيح!
I said it is not true!
قلت هذا ليس صحيحا!
The weather is so nice.
الطقس جميل جدا.
Since it has been a while now...
منذ ذلك الحين ...
I'm so glad that man Tsueda is gone now.
أنا سعيد للغاية لأن الرجل تسويدا قد رحل الآن.
That scoundrel played tricks...
لعب هذا الوغد الحيل ...
and colluded like a rat,
وتواطأوا مثل الجرذ ،
and innocent people died because of that.
ومات الأبرياء بسبب ذلك.
And yet Kkeut Soe gets all worked up...
ومع ذلك ، فإن Kkeut Soe تعمل على كل شيء ...
and denies killing Tsueda.
وينفي قتل تسويدا.
Gosh, he's a trickster himself now.
يا إلهي ، هو نفسه محتال الآن.
Jang Hyun, Kkeut Soe is...
جانغ هيون ، Kkeut Soe ...
a dumb man who is innately bad at lying.
رجل غبي سيء بالفطرة في الكذب.
But could it have been you who ordered him to kill Tsueda?
لكن هل من الممكن أن تكون أنت من أمرته بقتل تسويدا؟
But why?
لكن لماذا؟
Why? Because I am a terrible man myself.
لماذا؟  لأنني رجل فظيع.
Gosh.
يا الهي.
Hold it.
أمسك به.
- It's going up. - I am holding it.
- إنها ترتفع.  - أنا أحمله.
- Wait. - That's it.
- انتظر.  - هذا كل شيء.
Move it.
حركه.
- Take this. - Okay.
- خد هذا.  - تمام.
Here.
هنا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
There.
هناك.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
It's turning out nicely.
انها تتحول بشكل جيد.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
That's right.
صحيح.
Sixty years ago,
قبل ستين عاما ،
I was working in the field,
كنت أعمل في الميدان ،
and when I heard the bride was coming,
وعندما سمعت أن العروس قادمة ،
I quickly washed my face in the stream and went down.
غسلت وجهي بسرعة في الدفق ونزلت.
I did not deserve a bride.
لم أستحق عروساً.
But you see,
لكن انظر،
from a distance, a girl walked down cheerfully.
من مسافة بعيدة ، نزلت فتاة بمرح.
A girl looking like a full moon...
فتاة تشبه البدر ...
came with just one bundle.
جاء بحزمة واحدة فقط.
I could not bring myself up to speak to her,
لم أستطع إحضار نفسي للتحدث معها ،
so I snatched her bundle and walked.
لذلك انتزعت حزقتها وسرت.
I did not enter the bride's room,
لم أدخل غرفة العروس
and I kept on drinking.
وظللت أشرب.
People said...
قال الناس ...
it was because the bride could not speak.
كان ذلك لأن العروس لم تستطع الكلام.
They talked in whispers.
تحدثوا في همسات.
But that was not it.
لكن لم يكن هذا هو.
I am sorry about that.
أنا آسف بشأن ذلك.
I was just a lowly farmer.
كنت مجرد مزارع متواضع.
How did I deserve a beautiful bride like her?
كيف أستحق عروساً جميلة مثلها؟
I got her.
لقد حصلت عليها.
I will make her the most beautiful bride in the world.
سأجعلها أجمل عروس في العالم.
- Congratulations.
- تهانينا.  - تهانينا.
- Hold on tight. - Let us help you.
- تمسك جيدا.  - دعنا نساعدك.
- Careful. - My goodness.
- حذر.  - رباه.
Here.
هنا.
Lastly.
أخيرا.
Lee Jang Hyun said he would arrive on time for the 60th wedding anniversary party.
قال Lee Jang Hyun إنه سيصل في الوقت المحدد لحفل الذكرى الستين للزواج.
What did I tell you?
ماذا أخبرتك؟
You should not trust him too much.
يجب ألا تثق به كثيرًا.
He is here.
هو هنا.
The rice is here.
الأرز هنا.
Is that rice?
هل هذا رز؟
That is rice, is it not?
هذا هو الأرز ، أليس كذلك؟
It is rice.
إنه أرز.
It has come.
هو جاء.
It arrived.
وصل.
All right.
حسنًا.
Here comes the groom.
هنا يأتي العريس.
Look at the groom.
انظر إلى العريس.
Welcome.
مرحباً.
Here comes the bride.
هنا تأتي العروس.
She is beautiful.
انها جميلة.
The bride drinks.
العروس يشرب.
The groom drinks...
العريس يشرب ...
in return.
فى المقابل.
- Bless you.
- بارك الله فيك.  - بارك الله فيك.
- Live long.
- عش طويلا.  - عش طويلا.
- What? - Who is he?
- ماذا؟  - من هو؟
I would like to sing for this precious event.
أود أن أغني لهذا الحدث الثمين.
- He is going to sing. - Who is he?
- سيغني.  - من هو؟
He is going to sing.
سوف يغني.
I am looking from afar
أنا أنظر من بعيد
At your endearing face
في وجهك المحبب
The face that I missed
الوجه الذي فاتني
Was carried
تم حمله
By the distant wind
بواسطة الريح البعيدة
You are like me
انت مثلي
Burying your face in your hands
دفن وجهك بين يديك
The moment
اللحظة
I was waiting for
كنت انتظر
Walk on that path
امش على هذا الطريق
Even when you waver
حتى عندما ترتد
In the moonlight
في ضوء القمر
So she had a crush on someone.
لذلك كانت معجبة بشخص ما.
Come on.
تعال.
Today, I will make an offer to Yeon Jun which he cannot turn down.
اليوم ، سأقدم عرضًا لـ Yeon Jun لا يمكنه رفضه.
Turn down...
رفض...
What?
ماذا؟
- I will kiss him. - My goodness!
- سأقبله.  - رباه!
What if Lord Yoo finds out?
ماذا لو اكتشف اللورد يو ذلك؟
How would Father find out?
كيف يكتشف الأب؟
So hurry up and fetch Young Master Yeon Jun.
لذلك أسرع وأحضر السيد الشاب يون جون.
Tell him my face suddenly turned purple, then I fainted.
أخبره أن وجهي تحول فجأة إلى اللون الأرجواني ، ثم أغمي علي.
Hurry, Jong Jong. Go on!
على عجل ، جونغ جونغ.  تابع!
Like this?
مثله؟
No.
لا.
Maybe here.
ربما هنا.
Young Master Yeon Jun.
السيد الشاب يون Jun.
My lady! Goodness.
سيدتي!  صلاح.
My lady!
سيدتي!
Young Master Yeon Jun.
السيد الشاب يون Jun.
You are covered in sweat.
أنت مغطى بالعرق.
You should have some water.
يجب أن يكون لديك بعض الماء.
- Jong Jong! - No, it is okay.
- جونغ جونغ!  - لا ، لا بأس.
I was just surprised for a moment.
لقد فوجئت فقط للحظة.
Jong Jong.
الشباب الشباب.
You were surprised?
هل فوجئت؟
You are always brave and strong. What happened?
أنت دائما شجاع وقوي.  ماذا حدث؟
"Brave and strong?"
"شجاع وقوي؟"
What are you talking about?
عن ماذا تتحدث؟
I cannot even harm a fly.
لا أستطيع حتى أن أؤذي ذبابة.
My gosh!
يا إلهي!
You little... Go away.
أنت صغير ... اذهب بعيدا.
How embarrassing.
كم هذا محرج.
My lady, I flicked it away.
سيدتي ، لقد قمت برميها بعيدًا.
Are you all right?
هل انت بخير؟
Young Master Yeon Jun.
السيد الشاب يون Jun.
I have been...
لقد كنت...
trying to feel you out...
أحاول أن أشعر بالخارج ...
without revealing how I truly felt. It must have been frustrating for you.
دون الكشف عن شعوري حقًا.  لا بد أنه كان محبطًا لك.
Now, I wish to tell you.
الآن ، أود أن أخبرك.
Yes.
نعم.
I feel the same way as you do.
أشعر بنفس الطريقة التي تشعر بها.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
My lady.
سيدتي.
I am engaged to Lady Eun Ae.
أنا مخطوبة للسيدة إيون آي.
Who cares about a promise you made when you were little?
من يهتم بوعد قطعته عندما كنت صغيرًا؟
That promise is not the reason I am staying by Lady Eun Ae's side.
هذا الوعد ليس سبب بقائي بجانب السيدة إيون آي.
I...
أنا...
truly care for her.
تهتم بها حقًا.
Then...
ثم...
what about those glances...
ماذا عن تلك النظرات ...
and the sweet words you said to me?
والكلمات الحلوة التي قلتها لي؟
Did you lead me on to mess with me?
هل قادتني للعبث معي؟
You are my teacher's daughter...
أنت ابنة أستاذي ...
and Lady Eun Ae's favorite friend, so...
والصديق المفضل للسيدة إيون آي ، لذا ...
So?
لذا؟
You were just being nice to me?
كنت مجرد لطيفة معي؟
You are lying.
انت تكذب.
It is all a lie.
كل ذلك هو كذب.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
I know that you...
أعلم أنك ...
This never happened.
هذا لم يحدث قط.
I was the first one.
كنت الأول.
I fell for you first,
لقد وقعت في حبك أولا ،
and you and Eun Ae met because of me.
وأنت و Eun Ae التقيا بسببي.
- I loved you first... - Gil Chae!
- أحببتك أولاً ... - جيل تشاي!
Gil Chae.
جيل تشاي.
I saved you from being made fun of for a thousand years to come.
لقد أنقذتك من السخرية منك لألف عام قادمة.
Gil Chae!
جيل تشاي!
I heard she fainted. Where did she go?
سمعت أنها أغمي عليها.  إلى أين ذهبت؟
I wonder where she is.
أتساءل أين هي.
Lady Gil Chae!
سيدة جيل تشاي!
You were eavesdropping?
كنت تتنصت؟
"Eavesdropping?" No.
"التنصت؟"  لا.
How could I not hear that loud love confession?
كيف لا أسمع هذا الاعتراف الصاخب بالحب؟
How rude!
كم هو وقح!
So in short, you loved your friend's fiancé?
باختصار ، هل أحببت خطيبة صديقك؟
It is similar to one of the stories I heard at the market.
إنها مشابهة لإحدى القصص التي سمعتها في السوق.
A wrongful encounter...
لقاء خاطئ ...
that should have never happened.
ما كان يجب أن يحدث.
Here is the full story.
إليك القصة الكاملة.
"I trusted my friend as much as I trusted you."
"لقد وثقت في صديقي بقدر ما وثقت بك."
"Hence, I casually introduced you to my friend."
"ومن ثم ، قدمت لك صديقي عرضًا."
"After that, the three of us spent time together often."
"بعد ذلك ، قضينا نحن الثلاثة وقتًا معًا كثيرًا".
"We had fun..."
"استمتعنا..."
"and hung out together."
"وقضوا معا."
So you had a crush on Yeon Jun?
إذن ، هل كنت معجبًا بـ Yeon Jun؟
Oh, right.
صحيح.
Was he the man you were waiting for by the swings?
هل كان هو الرجل الذي كنت تنتظره بجوار المراجيح؟
Goodness. I heard there was a fox with 99 tails in Neunggun-ri...
صلاح.  سمعت أن هناك ثعلبًا ب 99 ذيلًا في نيونغون ري ...
and was excited to see what you could do.
وكان متحمسًا لمعرفة ما يمكنك فعله.
But you cannot even win a man's heart?
لكن لا يمكنك حتى الفوز بقلب الرجل؟
Are you...
أنت...
done talking?
هل انتهيت من الحديث؟
What was I saying?
ماذا كنت أقول؟
Right.
يمين.
A fox...
الثعلب...
with 99 tails.
مع 99 ذيول.
I can keep rambling on until my casket gets closed.
يمكنني الاستمرار في المشي حتى يتم إغلاق النعش الخاص بي.
But what I truly wish to say is this.
لكن ما أود قوله حقًا هو هذا.
I do not think you stand a chance with him, so...
لا أعتقد أن لديك فرصة معه ، لذا ...
Shut your mouth.
اصمت.
So give up false hope and...
لذا تخلوا عن الأمل الزائف و ...
I told you to shut your mouth.
قلت لك أن تسكت فمك.
Come to me.
تعالى لي.
Are you proposing to me right now?
هل تقترح علي الآن؟
What? Nonsense.
ماذا؟  كلام فارغ.
You already know...
انت تعرف بالفعل...
that I do not believe in marriage...
اني لا اؤمن بالزواج ...
Right, you do not wish to get married.
صحيح ، أنت لا ترغب في الزواج.
Why get married...
لماذا تتزوج ...
and kill the romance in your heart?
وتقتل الرومانسية في قلبك؟
Even if you are madly in love,
حتى لو كنت في حالة حب بجنون ،
the excitement and passion quickly fizzle out.
الإثارة والعاطفة تتلاشى بسرعة.
My point is,
ما أود أن أشير له هو،
why not forget about marriage as it is nothing but a hassle?
لماذا لا تنسى الزواج لأنه ليس سوى متاعب؟
How about we passionately...
ماذا عننا بشغف ...
"Passionately?"
"بحماس؟"
How about we make love to each other?
ماذا لو نمارس الحب مع بعضنا البعض؟
I do not say this to every woman I meet.
أنا لا أقول هذا لكل امرأة أقابلها.
I cannot have a conversation like this with other women.
لا يمكنني إجراء محادثة كهذه مع نساء أخريات.
However,
لكن،
you are...
أنت...
gutsy.
جريء.
I think we can see eye to eye.
أعتقد أننا يمكن أن نرى وجها لوجه.
Finally, you are showing your true colors.
أخيرًا ، أنت تُظهر ألوانك الحقيقية.
Are you smitten by me?
هل أنت مغرم بي؟
Well, since you are a man too,
حسنًا ، بما أنك رجل أيضًا ،
it is only natural you feel that way.
من الطبيعي أن تشعر بهذه الطريقة.
The moment you first see me, you feel like you can't breathe.
في اللحظة التي تراني فيها لأول مرة ، تشعر أنك لا تستطيع التنفس.
The second time you see me, you feel your heart wanting me.
في المرة الثانية التي تراني فيها ، تشعر أن قلبك يريدني.
And the third time, you become lovesick.
وفي المرة الثالثة ، تصبح مغرمًا بالحب.
So you'd cry your eyes out like a kid and get all clingy.
لذلك كنت تبكي عينيك مثل طفل وتتشبث كل شيء.
That is...
إنه...
the truth behind the mysterious disease that has affected every man in this town.
حقيقة المرض الغامض الذي أصاب كل رجل في هذه البلدة.
It begins when you fall for me.
يبدأ عندما تقع من أجلي.
But you know what?
ولكن هل تعلم؟
I...
أنا...
hate your guts.
أكره شجاعتك.
You hate me?
انت تكرهني؟
That much?
بهذا القدر؟
Yes, I hate you.
نعم أنا أكرهك.
I suppose you have broken many women's hearts...
أفترض أنك كسرت قلوب الكثير من النساء ...
while living a hedonistic lifestyle.
بينما يعيش أسلوب حياة مفعمة بالمرح.
But I will not fall for your tricks,
لكنني لن أسقط في حيلك ،
so have fun for just a few more days and leave.
لذا استمتع بوقتك لبضعة أيام أخرى ثم غادر.
- Do not wreak havoc on my village. - Wait, stop.
- لا تعيث فسادا في قريتي.  - انتظر ، توقف.
Why not me?
لماذا ليس أنا؟
You want to know?
أنت تريدأنتعرف؟
Are you sure you can handle what I am about to say?
هل أنت متأكد من أنك تستطيع التعامل مع ما سأقوله؟
You converse with foreign intruders, which is wrong.
أنت تتحدث مع الدخلاء الأجانب ، وهذا خطأ.
You purposely mislead your elders with your sweet words.
أنت تضلل شيوخك عمدًا بكلماتك الحلوة.
I caught you eavesdropping on me hiding like a little rat.
لقد ضبطتك تتنصت علي مختبئًا مثل فأر صغير.
You dared to grab a woman's wrist...
لقد تجرأت على الإمساك بمعصم امرأة ...
and rudely bothered her.
وأزعجها بوقاحة.
You stole women's hearts...
سرقت قلوب النساء ...
and ran away like a loser. But what?
وهرب مثل الخاسر.  ولكن ماذا؟
You do not believe in marriage?
أنت لا تؤمن بالزواج؟
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
And most importantly,
و الاهم من ذلك،
I do not like that face of yours.
أنا لا أحب وجهك هذا.
You are ugly.
أنت قبيح.
Darling, my husband
حبيبي زوجي
My darling
يا عزيزى
- She is here. - Love
- إنها هنا.  - حب
My love
حبيبي
It is love
انه الحب
It is definitely love
إنه حب بالتأكيد
Goodness, it is love
الخير هو الحب
Moon, bright moon
القمر ، القمر الساطع
No matter how busy you are
مهما كنت مشغولا
They...
هم...
were talking behind my back again.
كانوا يتحدثون خلف ظهري مرة أخرى.
What did they say this time?
ماذا قالوا هذه المرة؟
They said you would end up...
قالوا أنك ستنتهي ...
(Kyohyung: death by hanging)
(Kyohyung: الموت شنقا)
like Uhwudong who was executed for committing adultery.
مثل Uhwudong الذي أعدم بتهمة الزنا.
(Uhwudong: a woman from the Joseon dynasty...)
(Uhwudong: امرأة من سلالة جوسون ...)
(who was executed for committing adultery)
(الذي أعدم بتهمة الزنا)
They are so mean.
إنهم لئيمون جدا.
I wish I was like Uhwudong...
أتمنى لو كنت مثل Uhwudong ...
and had more room in my heart for other men.
وكان لدي مساحة أكبر في قلبي للرجال الآخرين.
I just want to...
أريد فقط...
give my unchanging love to a person who is unchanging.
أعط حبي الذي لا يتغير لشخص لا يتغير.
Are you saying Young Master Yeon Jun is unchanging?
هل تقول أن السيد الشاب يون جون لا يتغير؟
Yes.
نعم.
Young Master Yeon Jun does not change.
السيد الشاب يون جون لا يتغير.
Men have no fidelity or discipline,
الرجال ليس لديهم إخلاص أو انضباط ،
so they are always looking for prettier flowers,
لذلك هم يبحثون دائمًا عن أزهار أجمل ،
but Young Master Yeon Jun is different.
لكن السيد الشاب يون جون مختلف.
With the person I love,
مع الشخص الذي أحبه ،
I just want to go see flowers in the spring,
أريد فقط أن أذهب لرؤية الزهور في الربيع ،
dip my feet with him in a stream in the summer,
اغمس قدمي معه في مجرى مائي في الصيف ،
and in the winter, I want to drink the wine that we made in the fall.
وفي الشتاء أريد أن أشرب النبيذ الذي صنعناه في الخريف.
I just want to grow old with the person I love.
أريد فقط أن أتقدم في العمر مع الشخص الذي أحبه.
Is that the life that you want to live?
هل هذه هي الحياة التي تريد أن تعيشها؟
Do not make tomorrow come
لا تجعل الغد يأتي
Do not grow old
لا تكبر
And stay like this
وابقى هكذا
For a hundred years
لمائة عام
It is love, my love
إنه حب حبي
Goodness, my love
الخير حبي
They say a couple will grow old together if it snows on their wedding day.
يقولون إن الزوجين سيكبران معًا إذا تساقطت الثلوج في يوم زفافهما.
May the both of you live long and prosper.
أتمنى أن يعيش كلاكما طويلا ويزدهر.
- Live long and prosper!
- عش طويلا وازدهر!  - عش طويلا وازدهر!
Disguise yourselves as tradesmen,
تنكروا بأنفسكم كتجار ،
and ride with all your might...
واركب بكل قوتك ...
to besiege the palace where the king of Joseon is.
لمحاصرة القصر حيث يوجد ملك جوسون.
Do not waste your time fighting each fortress in Joseon.
لا تضيعوا وقتكم في قتال كل حصن في جوسون.
You must enter Hanyang...
يجب أن تدخل Hanyang ...
before the Joseon king flees to Ganghwa,
قبل أن يفر ملك جوسون إلى كانغهوا ،
and wait.
و انتظر.
The foreign intruders are here!
الدخلاء الأجانب هنا!
The intruders...
الدخلاء ...
They...
هم...
took His Majesty captive!
أخذ جلالة الملك في الأسر!
- What did he say? - What is he saying?
- ماذا قال؟  - ماذا يقول؟
What is he saying?
ماذا يقول؟
- What is going on?
- ماذا يقول؟  - ما الذي يجري؟
Is he saying the truth?
هل يقول الحقيقة؟
Are you being serious?
هل انت جاد؟
(My Dearest)
(أعز ما عندي)
The people of Joseon, let us save His Majesty!
يا شعب جوسون فلننقذ جلالة الملك!
Those with a burning heart, come forward!
أولئك الذين لديهم قلب محترق ، تقدموا!
I will go! Is there no one else?
سأذهب!  لا يوجد أحد آخر؟
I can help.
يمكنني المساعدة.
He could die.
يمكن أن يموت.
We have to stop them.
علينا أن نوقفهم.
Stop the army from fighting.
أوقفوا القتال عن الجيش.
My lady,
سيدتي،
The country is being invaded and the king is being held captive.
يتم غزو البلاد والملك محتجز.
If you step onto the battlefield, the violent intruders will...
إذا خطوت إلى ساحة المعركة ، فإن المتسللين العنيفين سوف ...
Then if I am lucky enough to come back alive,
ثم إذا حالفني الحظ لأعود على قيد الحياة ،
allow me to kiss your precious lips.
اسمح لي أن أقبّل شفتيك الغاليتين.
Ripped and resynced by YoungJedi
ممزق ومزامنة بواسطة YoungJedi